<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>VICKY STEEVES (Posts about amnh)</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://vickysteeves.com/categories/amnh.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 20:53:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Preserving Scientific Research Data at the American Museum of Natural History</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.archivists.org/sites/all/files/MAS%20Newsletter%20Summer%202015-new.pdf"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;As the National Digital Stewardship Resident at the American Museum of Natural History, I was introduced to the very specific problems facing museum librarians and archivists not only through observing the Research Library, but by speaking individually with some of the most intensive data creators at the Museum. As a part of my larger needs assessment project at the Museum, I created a semi-structured interview guide that I used to enter into a targeted dialogue with scientific staff members, covering all aspects of their digital research and collections data. Topics included the volume of their data, its rate of growth, format types, necessary software and hardware support, management practices, and opinions on preservation of their data (i.e. what data they believe is important in the long-term). I interviewed close to 60 staff members in total, including all the curators in the five Science divisions at the Museum: Anthropology, Invertebrate Zoology, Paleontology, Physical Sciences, and Vertebrate Zoology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>digital preservation</category><category>ndsr</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Project Update: DONE WITH ANALYSIS</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/project-update-analysis/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/project-update/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Originally, I had my presentation scheduled for about 10 minutes but due to time constraints on the agenda, it was shortened to five. This meant I speed-talked my way through all the analyses I had finished the Friday before (April 3) while hoping to impress on everyone there that the risk of data loss is not only imminent, but inevitable. Given the questions and comments I received directly after my presentation and in the week to come, I can say this presentation was a definite success.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;For the Residency itself, all I have left to do is my final report--this is a compilation of my previous reports and analyses with recommendations for storage, management, and preservation of the Museum’s vast scientific collections and research data. These previous reports include: a plan for the length of retention for digital assets, an environmental scan to see what other similar institutions are doing for their data, and an overview of what federal agencies fund AMNH research, and whether those agencies require data management plans or not. All these previous reports will come together to form my recommendations as well as provide the Museum with the information it needs to understand and interpret my recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/project-update-analysis/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/project-update-analysis/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Party on, AMNH!</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/party-on-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/party-on-amnh/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Vicky here to bring you some holiday cheer. I thought, since this is our last post before Hanukkah, Yule, Life Day, Festivus, Kwanzaa , Pancha Ganapati, Soyal, the Dongzhi Festival, Christmas, Newtonmas, Boxing Day, Omisoka, and New Years, I could wind down a busy few months by talking about the American Museum of Natural History party season!&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Just about every day of the week, starting from the 10th of December to the 19th, there is a party at the AMNH. Each department has their own parties, some are small and attended mostly by people within the department; others are all staff events with food, drinks, and music.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;The Library kicked off the party season this year, with probably 50+ people eating and drinking in the reading room (it’s only one night of the year, librarian friends who are cringing!) as the night went on.  This was a great opportunity for me to better get to know many of the scientists that I've interviewed for my NDSR project in a more informal environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/party-on-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>ndsr</category><category>personal</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/party-on-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>