<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>VICKY STEEVES (Posts about NDSR-Blog)</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://vickysteeves.com/categories/cat_ndsr-blog.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 20:53:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>So Long, Farewell, Auf Wiedersehen, Adieu</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/solong-farewell/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Written collaboratively by the &lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/2014-2015-residents/"&gt;NDSR 2014/15 Cohort&lt;/a&gt; for the NDSR-NY Residents' Blog. &lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/so-long-farewell-auf-wiedersehen-adieu/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
		&lt;p&gt;Well folks, this marks the final post from the 2014-15 NDSR-NY cohort. Before we officially sign off we wanted to say a big thank you to everyone who has followed our journeys via this blog, and offer some final thoughts on what the residency has meant to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/solong-farewell/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/solong-farewell/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>So you've decided to apply to NDSR....</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/NDSR-application-advice/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Written collaboratively by the &lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/2014-2015-residents/"&gt;NDSR 2014/15 Cohort&lt;/a&gt; for the NDSR-NY Residents' Blog. &lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/so-youve-decided-to-apply-to-ndsr/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Applications to the 2015-16 National Digital Stewardship Residencies in New York are open! The deadline to apply has been extended by two weeks, to &lt;b&gt;Friday, May 22&lt;/b&gt;! Woo! As if you needed more good news than that, METRO also recently announced the host institutions for this round of residencies, and they’re very exciting (like we’d probably compete with you for them if we could!). You can learn all about them and their projects &lt;a title="NDSR 2015-16 hosts and projects" href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/projects-201516/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;As the the current cohort round the corner and bring their 2014-15 residencies into the home stretch, we’re frequently asked for our advice to prospective Residents, those of you considering applying to the program (most important advice: do it!). We touched on some of these themes in &lt;a title="METRO: CATCHING UP WITH OUR NDSR RESIDENTS PART 2" href="http://metro.org/articles/catching-up-with-our-ndsr-residents-part-2/"&gt;our most recent interview with METRO&lt;/a&gt;. Here, in the meantime, are our summary responses to those questions most frequently asked of us live and online:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/NDSR-application-advice/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/NDSR-application-advice/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Project Update: DONE WITH ANALYSIS</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/project-update-analysis/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/project-update/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Originally, I had my presentation scheduled for about 10 minutes but due to time constraints on the agenda, it was shortened to five. This meant I speed-talked my way through all the analyses I had finished the Friday before (April 3) while hoping to impress on everyone there that the risk of data loss is not only imminent, but inevitable. Given the questions and comments I received directly after my presentation and in the week to come, I can say this presentation was a definite success.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;For the Residency itself, all I have left to do is my final report--this is a compilation of my previous reports and analyses with recommendations for storage, management, and preservation of the Museum’s vast scientific collections and research data. These previous reports include: a plan for the length of retention for digital assets, an environmental scan to see what other similar institutions are doing for their data, and an overview of what federal agencies fund AMNH research, and whether those agencies require data management plans or not. All these previous reports will come together to form my recommendations as well as provide the Museum with the information it needs to understand and interpret my recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/project-update-analysis/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/project-update-analysis/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NMNH, METRO, &amp; Outsourcing, oh my!</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/nmnh-metro-outsourcing/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/outsourcing/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone!! So, like Karl, I was recently asked to write a post on another blog (&lt;a href="http://www.mnh.si.edu/rc/fieldbooks/"&gt;The Smithsonian Field book Project blog!&lt;/a&gt;) and thought, instead of rewriting the whole post and publishing it here, I could just point our lovely readers in the right direction!&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;The post on the Smithsonian Field book Project blog details the specific interactions I've had at the American Museum of Natural History with field books. The majority of my experience with field books was actually initiated by the curators and scientific staff that I interviewed--they will often talk about how invaluable their field notes and lab notes are to maintaining the long-term viability and usability of their research data, or how older field books are incredibly impactful to their ongoing projects. For those that don't know, field books are essentially notebooks that scientists bring into the field to record their observations and findings. There are a few tidbits in my post about how field books are necessary as primary source documentation for ongoing and current scientific research. Basically--there are really cool old field books at the Museum and they are &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;still&lt;/span&gt; relevant to science!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/nmnh-metro-outsourcing/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ndsr</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/nmnh-metro-outsourcing/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>code4Lib 2015!</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/code4lib-2015/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/code4lib-2015/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, this is Vicky reporting from Portland, Oregon! I am here on the west coast for the first time attending &lt;a href="http://code4lib.org/conference/2015/"&gt;code4Lib 2015&lt;/a&gt;, and since today is the last day of the conference, I thought I’d give everyone a bit of a report about what went on here.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;First, I want to talk about the format of presentations at code4Lib. It’s absolutely unlike any other conference I’ve ever been too. There are no multiple sessions going at once. Everything is streamlined into one room. Yes--we sat in a room from 9-5pm watching 20 minute presentations, with an hour for lunch and two to three half hour breaks. This sounds really daunting but I have to tell you--it was so refreshing! I’ll talk a little bit more about the actual presentations later on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/code4lib-2015/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>ndsr</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/code4lib-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Library Advocacy</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/library-advocacy/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/library-advocacy/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Everyone reading my posts must be saying, “Damn, this girl is obsessed with proving the value of the library! We get it already!” Blame &lt;a href="http://www.simmons.edu/slis/faculty/fulltime/matarazzo.php"&gt;Jim Matarazzo&lt;/a&gt;, my corporate libraries professor back at &lt;a href="http://www.simmons.edu/slis/"&gt;Simmons&lt;/a&gt;. He really drilled it into my head that if a library can’t prove that it’s worth having, it will be the first thing cut from a budget. And it scared me into constantly thinking about it. Thanks, Jim!&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/prove-yourself-needs-assessment-edition/"&gt;In my last NDSR-NY post&lt;/a&gt;, I described how the needs assessment survey can be utilized to show value on an institutional level, in the setting of meetings with business operatives and institutional leaders. In my &lt;a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/digitalpreservation/2014/11/the-value-of-the-ndsr-residents-and-mentors-weigh-in/"&gt;blog post for the SIGNAL&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about how programs like NDSR can prove their value on an interdisciplinary level as well as to the LIS field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/library-advocacy/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>advocacy</category><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/library-advocacy/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Party on, AMNH!</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/party-on-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/party-on-amnh/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Vicky here to bring you some holiday cheer. I thought, since this is our last post before Hanukkah, Yule, Life Day, Festivus, Kwanzaa , Pancha Ganapati, Soyal, the Dongzhi Festival, Christmas, Newtonmas, Boxing Day, Omisoka, and New Years, I could wind down a busy few months by talking about the American Museum of Natural History party season!&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Just about every day of the week, starting from the 10th of December to the 19th, there is a party at the AMNH. Each department has their own parties, some are small and attended mostly by people within the department; others are all staff events with food, drinks, and music.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;The Library kicked off the party season this year, with probably 50+ people eating and drinking in the reading room (it’s only one night of the year, librarian friends who are cringing!) as the night went on.  This was a great opportunity for me to better get to know many of the scientists that I've interviewed for my NDSR project in a more informal environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/party-on-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>ndsr</category><category>personal</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/party-on-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Prove Yourself: Needs Assessment Edition</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/prove-yourself-needs-assessment/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/prove-yourself-needs-assessment-edition/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	  
			&lt;p&gt;What I’ve come to love about the library science field (which after years of waiting tables you’d think I’d hate) is the service aspect to everything we do. Librarians are intensely user-focused in all of our work: through the use of needs assessment surveys, we mold our libraries to what users want, expect, and need. We use the results to design programs, buy technology, even create positions within a library (YA librarian is a thing because of that!). Some common ways to implement a library assessment include  focus groups, interviews, scorecards, comment cards, usage statistics from circulation and reference, and surveys sent to users via email or on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

				&lt;p&gt;This past week, I attended a workshop with the fabulous &lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/author/jkim/"&gt;Julia Kim&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://metro.org/"&gt;METRO&lt;/a&gt; that focused on the implementation and design aspects of surveying, called "Assessment in Focus: Designing and Implementing an Effective User Feedback Survey." The presenter, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nisabakkalbasi"&gt;Nisa Bakkalbasi&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://library.columbia.edu/bts/assessment.html"&gt;assessment coordinator&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://library.columbia.edu/"&gt;Columbia University Libraries/Information Services&lt;/a&gt;, was a former statistician and presented on the many ways one could glean statistically valuable quantitative data from simple survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/prove-yourself-needs-assessment/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>assessment</category><category>ndsr</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/prove-yourself-needs-assessment/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science: The Final Frontier</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/ndsr-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/science-the-final-frontier/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;			
			
	  		&lt;p&gt;Science: the final frontier. These are the voyages of Vicky Steeves. Her nine-month mission: to explore how scientific data can be preserved more efficiently at &lt;a href="http://www.amnh.org/our-research"&gt;the American Museum of Natural History&lt;/a&gt;, to boldly interview every member of science staff involved in data creation and management, to go into the depths of the Museum where none have gone before.&lt;/p&gt;
		
			&lt;p&gt;Hi there. Digital preservation of scientific data is criminally under-addressed nationwide. Scientific research is increasingly digital and data intensive, with repositories and aggregators built everyday to house this data. Some popular aggregators in natural history include the NIH-funded &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/genbank"&gt;GenBank&lt;/a&gt; for DNA sequence data and the NSF funded &lt;a href="http://www.morphbank.net/"&gt;MorphBank&lt;/a&gt; for image data of specimens. These aggregators are places where scientists submit their data for dissemination and act as phenomenal tools for data sharing, however they cannot be relied upon for preservation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/ndsr-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>digital preservation</category><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/ndsr-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>