<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>VICKY STEEVES (Posts about conference report)</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://vickysteeves.com/categories/conference-report.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 20:53:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Visiting CERN</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/cern-visit/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, &lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/solong-farewell/"&gt;my NDSR cohort&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; I had the great opportunity to present &lt;a href="https://github.com/VickySteeves/2016-NDSR-CompetencyProfile-Paper/blob/master/2016-10-03_iPRES_NDSRLongPaper.pdf"&gt;our paper&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://www.ipres2016.ch/"&gt;iPres 2016&lt;/a&gt; in Bern, Switzerland! This was my first ever peer reviewed paper and it was accepted! Not a bad first time 😁. Our presentation went really well -- there was good audience engagement and it seemed like there was real potential for people to extend or use our study (with all our &lt;a href="https://osf.io/zndwq/"&gt;open access data&lt;/a&gt;!). One of my favourite moments was right after our presentation, when an audience member (whose name escapes me, I'm so sorry if you're reading this!) told us that we were part of very few people he'd seen accurately use grounded theory. I doubt this is true, but it was flattering nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
	  
	  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/cern-visit/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (17 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>ndsr</category><category>personal</category><category>presentation</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/cern-visit/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SHARE Week</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/share-week/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week I made my first trek down to Virginia to engage with the Center for Open Science IRL! After just about a year of emails, hangouts, and calls, I was excited to see the space in which I think some really innovative tech is being developed for the open X community. The second week of July was designated as SHARE week: Monday and Tuesday was the SHARE hackathon, Wednesday and half of Thursday was the SHARE community meeting, and the last half of Thursday and Friday was the SHARE Curation Associates kick off orientation. &lt;/p&gt;
	  
	  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/share-week/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (9 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/share-week/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>So. Many. Conferences.</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/so-many-conferences/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first two weeks of May have been just explicitly devoted to conferences. Planning, executing, attending, surveying -- you name it, I've been doing it in relation to some event or another. It's actually been great, but &lt;em&gt;so exhausting&lt;/em&gt;. I am definitely giving a lot of props to event planners for doing this as their day-to-day.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/so-many-conferences/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/so-many-conferences/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FORCE2016</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/force-2016/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;W.O.W.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;So, I kind of am in love with the &lt;a href="https://www.force11.org/meetings/force2016"&gt;FORCE conference&lt;/a&gt; I just went to. FORCE2016 is the annual conference from an organization called FORCE11 (ha, the year they started the org.). This year, 500 people came from around the world: researchers, librarians, software developers, large scale repositories, open science advocates, and everyone in between. It was not only a very diverse conference in terms of home country and job, but also in the way the conference and program was run.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;First, one of the coolest things I have ever seen: in addition to the MULTITUDE of tweets around the event (seriously everyone was so active, it was amazing), they hired a company to take visual notes!! While everything was going on!! Everyone, the gist of their talks, panels, lightning talks, EVERYTHING! Such a great idea and it produced a great visual overview of the con!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/force-2016/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/force-2016/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Presenting at CNI</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/presenting-CNI/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt; This month was excellent as it marked my first ever professional presentation as a NYU Librarian :) &lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Last year during NDSR, it seemed like I was giving a presentation at a conference, professional organization meeting, webinar, etc. every other week. It’s been exceptionally restful (well, sort of...) to spend these past 5 months getting to know NYU, my colleagues, the scope of my work, and really just getting a feel for my day-to-day. &lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting outputs from my first semester here at NYU has surrounded my work on the Moore-Sloan Data Science Environment (msdse.org). Back in October (link to Oct 2015 post), I wrote about the MSDSE Summit that was held at Suncadia Resort in Washington state. God it was so incredibly beautiful there and I got to do some really cool stuff, but the best thing that happened was definitely meeting &lt;a href="http://guides.lib.uw.edu/friendly.php?s=research/jmuilenburg"&gt;Jenny Muilenburg&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://bids.berkeley.edu/people/erik-mitchell"&gt; Erik Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/presenting-CNI/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>presentation</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/presenting-CNI/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My First LITA</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/first-LITA/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I attend the &lt;a href="http://www.ala.org/lita/"&gt;Library Information Technology Association&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="http://litaforum.org/"&gt;Forum&lt;/a&gt;. Over the 13-15th, I attended several sessions, explored Minneapolis for the first time, and met some really awesome people. I was, as always, a bit nervous attending a new conference but the organizers had some really great 101-type sessions, and even set up &lt;a href="http://litaforum.slack.com/"&gt;a Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; which I found to be immensely helpful throughout the day. People organized dinners, discussed sessions in real-time, posed questions, and uploaded some hysterical gifs.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/first-LITA/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (10 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/first-LITA/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moore-Sloan Data Science Environment Summit: A Recap</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/msdse-summit/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year's Moore/Sloan Data Science Environment was in the beautiful Cascade Mountains at the Suncadia Resort in Cle Elum, Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
    						
		&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;RT &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/uwescience"&gt;@uwescience&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DSESummit?src=hash"&gt;#DSESummit&lt;/a&gt; is off to a sunny start! &lt;a href="http://t.co/fQi3EZpSdL"&gt;pic.twitter.com/fQi3EZpSdL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Vicky Steeves (@VickySteeves) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VickySteeves/status/651068136075198464"&gt;October 5, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
		&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
		&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Look how beautiful that is. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/msdse-summit/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>nyu</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/msdse-summit/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>code4Lib 2015!</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/code4lib-2015/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/code4lib-2015/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, this is Vicky reporting from Portland, Oregon! I am here on the west coast for the first time attending &lt;a href="http://code4lib.org/conference/2015/"&gt;code4Lib 2015&lt;/a&gt;, and since today is the last day of the conference, I thought I’d give everyone a bit of a report about what went on here.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;First, I want to talk about the format of presentations at code4Lib. It’s absolutely unlike any other conference I’ve ever been too. There are no multiple sessions going at once. Everything is streamlined into one room. Yes--we sat in a room from 9-5pm watching 20 minute presentations, with an hour for lunch and two to three half hour breaks. This sounds really daunting but I have to tell you--it was so refreshing! I’ll talk a little bit more about the actual presentations later on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/code4lib-2015/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>ndsr</category><category>professional development</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/code4lib-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>