<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>VICKY STEEVES (Posts about digital preservation)</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://vickysteeves.com/categories/digital-preservation.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 20:53:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Preserving Scientific Research Data at the American Museum of Natural History</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.archivists.org/sites/all/files/MAS%20Newsletter%20Summer%202015-new.pdf"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;As the National Digital Stewardship Resident at the American Museum of Natural History, I was introduced to the very specific problems facing museum librarians and archivists not only through observing the Research Library, but by speaking individually with some of the most intensive data creators at the Museum. As a part of my larger needs assessment project at the Museum, I created a semi-structured interview guide that I used to enter into a targeted dialogue with scientific staff members, covering all aspects of their digital research and collections data. Topics included the volume of their data, its rate of growth, format types, necessary software and hardware support, management practices, and opinions on preservation of their data (i.e. what data they believe is important in the long-term). I interviewed close to 60 staff members in total, including all the curators in the five Science divisions at the Museum: Anthropology, Invertebrate Zoology, Paleontology, Physical Sciences, and Vertebrate Zoology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>digital preservation</category><category>ndsr</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science: The Final Frontier</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/ndsr-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/science-the-final-frontier/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;			
			
	  		&lt;p&gt;Science: the final frontier. These are the voyages of Vicky Steeves. Her nine-month mission: to explore how scientific data can be preserved more efficiently at &lt;a href="http://www.amnh.org/our-research"&gt;the American Museum of Natural History&lt;/a&gt;, to boldly interview every member of science staff involved in data creation and management, to go into the depths of the Museum where none have gone before.&lt;/p&gt;
		
			&lt;p&gt;Hi there. Digital preservation of scientific data is criminally under-addressed nationwide. Scientific research is increasingly digital and data intensive, with repositories and aggregators built everyday to house this data. Some popular aggregators in natural history include the NIH-funded &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/genbank"&gt;GenBank&lt;/a&gt; for DNA sequence data and the NSF funded &lt;a href="http://www.morphbank.net/"&gt;MorphBank&lt;/a&gt; for image data of specimens. These aggregators are places where scientists submit their data for dissemination and act as phenomenal tools for data sharing, however they cannot be relied upon for preservation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/ndsr-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>digital preservation</category><category>ndsr</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/ndsr-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>