<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>VICKY STEEVES (Posts about publication)</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://vickysteeves.com/categories/publication.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 20:53:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Visiting CERN</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/cern-visit/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, &lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/solong-farewell/"&gt;my NDSR cohort&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; I had the great opportunity to present &lt;a href="https://github.com/VickySteeves/2016-NDSR-CompetencyProfile-Paper/blob/master/2016-10-03_iPRES_NDSRLongPaper.pdf"&gt;our paper&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://www.ipres2016.ch/"&gt;iPres 2016&lt;/a&gt; in Bern, Switzerland! This was my first ever peer reviewed paper and it was accepted! Not a bad first time 😁. Our presentation went really well -- there was good audience engagement and it seemed like there was real potential for people to extend or use our study (with all our &lt;a href="https://osf.io/zndwq/"&gt;open access data&lt;/a&gt;!). One of my favourite moments was right after our presentation, when an audience member (whose name escapes me, I'm so sorry if you're reading this!) told us that we were part of very few people he'd seen accurately use grounded theory. I doubt this is true, but it was flattering nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
	  
	  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/cern-visit/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (17 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference report</category><category>ndsr</category><category>personal</category><category>presentation</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/cern-visit/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Preserving Scientific Research Data at the American Museum of Natural History</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.archivists.org/sites/all/files/MAS%20Newsletter%20Summer%202015-new.pdf"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;As the National Digital Stewardship Resident at the American Museum of Natural History, I was introduced to the very specific problems facing museum librarians and archivists not only through observing the Research Library, but by speaking individually with some of the most intensive data creators at the Museum. As a part of my larger needs assessment project at the Museum, I created a semi-structured interview guide that I used to enter into a targeted dialogue with scientific staff members, covering all aspects of their digital research and collections data. Topics included the volume of their data, its rate of growth, format types, necessary software and hardware support, management practices, and opinions on preservation of their data (i.e. what data they believe is important in the long-term). I interviewed close to 60 staff members in total, including all the curators in the five Science divisions at the Museum: Anthropology, Invertebrate Zoology, Paleontology, Physical Sciences, and Vertebrate Zoology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amnh</category><category>digital preservation</category><category>ndsr</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/preserving-science-data-amnh/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NMNH, METRO, &amp; Outsourcing, oh my!</title><link>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/nmnh-metro-outsourcing/</link><dc:creator>Vicky Steeves</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndsr.nycdigital.org/outsourcing/"&gt;See original posting here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone!! So, like Karl, I was recently asked to write a post on another blog (&lt;a href="http://www.mnh.si.edu/rc/fieldbooks/"&gt;The Smithsonian Field book Project blog!&lt;/a&gt;) and thought, instead of rewriting the whole post and publishing it here, I could just point our lovely readers in the right direction!&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;The post on the Smithsonian Field book Project blog details the specific interactions I've had at the American Museum of Natural History with field books. The majority of my experience with field books was actually initiated by the curators and scientific staff that I interviewed--they will often talk about how invaluable their field notes and lab notes are to maintaining the long-term viability and usability of their research data, or how older field books are incredibly impactful to their ongoing projects. For those that don't know, field books are essentially notebooks that scientists bring into the field to record their observations and findings. There are a few tidbits in my post about how field books are necessary as primary source documentation for ongoing and current scientific research. Basically--there are really cool old field books at the Museum and they are &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;still&lt;/span&gt; relevant to science!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vickysteeves.com/blog/nmnh-metro-outsourcing/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ndsr</category><category>publication</category><guid>http://vickysteeves.com/blog/nmnh-metro-outsourcing/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:08:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>